I'm Sara Al Mughairy, a strategic designer with roots in research and a talent for translating data into user-centered products.

Contact

Phone_951.541.3568
Email_sawra.tech@gmail.com
Portfolio_sawra.tech

UX

Skills_Ideation / Wireframing / Storyboarding / Personas / Journey Mapping / Card Sorting / Rapid Prototyping / User interviews / Focus Group / Field and Diary Studies / Usability Testing / Heuristic Analysis / User Stories

Tools_ Adobe CC / Sketch / Invision / Principle

Strategy

Skills_Stakeholder Mapping
/ Pitching / Video Production
/ Market Research

Marketing_Produced video ads that won or placed in 10 contests by major brands including Hilton, Nespresso, and Belvita

Engineering

Stack_JavaScript/HTML/
CSS3/ React/Redux/Node/
Express/Sequelize/Git/
SQL/Bootstrap

Work Experience

Sep 2014 - Nov 2015

UX Designer @ **UC Berkeley-Haas School of Business, NeuroEconomics Lab**Transformed laborious economic research paradigms into engaging iPhone games.
Note: Official job title was Research Data Analyst II from Mar - July 2015.

Sep 2013 - Jul 2015

Research Manager @ UC Berkeley Language and Cognitive Development Lab
Recruited, trained, and mentored over 30 RAs, Managed up to 8 studies at a time,
Launched Summer Internship program that attracted precocious students from all over the
country, Conducted international research with collaborators from Stanford, Yale, and UCSD,
Designed lab website, Co-wrote IRB's, grants, and publications.

Jun 2013 - Aug 2013

Research Assistant @ Harvard Lab for Developmental Studies

Iteratively modified experimental design to study participants as young as 18-months-old.

2010 - 2013, Undergraduate Research and Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant @ Northeastern University Intro to Cognitive Science Course Research Assistant @ EMD Serono Protein and Cell Sciences Lab Research Assistant @ Northeastern University NeuroPharmacology Lab

Education

Jan 2017 - May 2017

Software Engineering @ **Fullstack Academy** (top ranked coding bootcamp) 50 States of Code scholarship recipient, Won awards in two internal hackathons.

Sep 2015 - Aug 2016

Master of Human-Computer Interaction + Design @ University of Washington (3.98 GPA) Vice Chair of UW GPSS Diversity Committee, Organized HCl events for 100+ attendees such as the weekly Design-Use-Build seminar and graduation.

Sep 2010 - Jan 2013

BS. Behavioral Neuroscience @ Northeastern University (3.98 GPA)

Academic scholarship recipient, Sears B. Conduit Academic Achievement Award.

Highlights

2017_Designed, built, and launched startup, Video Turbine.

2016 Lead UX for two teams that made it to the UW Business Competition Investment Round.

2014 Published research conducted as an undergrad.

2013_Hand picked to set up and manage a new research lab at Cal.

2012_Convinced lab to try new resin for protein purification, ultimately doubling efficiency.

2012_Taught health classes in Boston Public Schools to help fill gap caused by budget cuts.